A Register of the Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection
circa 1870-1999
2004C50
Pathfinder Press.
31 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 3 card file boxes (14.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Collected by Pathfinder Press for use in illustrating its publications, the collection includes photographs, drawings, and printed reproductions of illustrations, depicting Leon Trotsky, leading figures of the Russian Revolution, leaders of the Fourth International, leaders of the Socialist Workers Party of the United States, and scenes related to all of the above.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biography Note
Pathfinder Press was established in New York City in 1969 as a successor to Pioneer Publishers (1930-1965) and Merit Publishers (1965-1969), and has been associated with the Socialist Workers Party. It has been the principal English-language publisher of works of Leon Trotsky, and has also published documentary works on the Communist International, Fourth International and Socialist Workers Party, writings of Fidel Castro, Nelson Mandela, Malcolm X and other American and international leftist leaders, and historical and analytical works on a variety of national and international political issues.
A Pathfinder Press Collection, donated by the Anchor Foundation, was established in the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992, and consists of record copies of publications of the press. This separate Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection was received from the Anchor Foundation in 2004.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection consists of photographs collected by the press for possible publication in books and pamphlets. There are also a small number of original drawings and cartoons. Cartoons by Laura Gray constitute the first series. The photographic series which follow include a Russian File (concentrating on the Russian Revolution and the history of the Bolshevik/Russian Communist Party through the 1920s), a Leon Trotsky File (depicting Trotsky at all stages of his life, but especially during his last three years in exile in Mexico), a Socialist Workers Party File (depicting leaders of the party from the 1920s through the 1990s), and a General Subject File (depicting Fourth International leaders from outside the United States, other notable leftist leaders from the United States and abroad, and world figures of all political stripes). There is also a small Publications File of photographs arranged by title of Pathfinder Press publication in which they appeared. Oversize items constitute a separate Oversize File.
Photographic prints often bear negative numbers on their backs. These will direct the user to a large file of negatives, arranged in numerical order. There is also a file of contact sheets, arranged numerically by negative number. An index card file of names of individuals depicted (mainly members or associates of the Socialist Workers Party) is also keyed to negative number.
Users of the Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection should be aware of the existence in the Hoover Institution Archives of the Pathfinder Press Collection consisting of copies of publications of the press, and also of The Militant Photographic Collection, consisting of photographs created or collected by the staff of The Militant, the newspaper associated with the Socialist Workers Party. Negatives of photographic prints to be found in the latter collection are interfiled in the Numerical Negative File of the Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 11 series, Cartoons, Russian File, Leon Trotsky File, Socialist Workers Party File, Oversize File, General Subject File, Publications File, Numerical Contact Sheets File, Numerical Negative File, Filmstrips, and Card File.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in Stanford University's online catalog.
Subjects
Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940--Pictorial works.; Fourth International--Pictorial works.; Socialist Workers Party--Pictorial works.; Communists--Pictorial works.; Revolutionaries--Pictorial works.; Communists--United States--Pictorial works.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Pictorial works.; Pathfinder Press.
Container List
- Cartoons, circa 1945-1957.
  Original cartoons and reproductions of cartoons by Laura Gray, mostly published in The Militant
  - Anti-labor legislation (Folder 1: 1)
  - Capitalism (Folder 1: 2)
  - Colonialism (Folder 1: 3)
  - Labor bureaucracy (Folder 1: 4)
  - Labor solidarity (Folder 1: 5)
  - Politicians (Folder 1: 6)
  - Racism and police brutality (Folder 1: 7)
  - Repression (Folder 1: 8)
  - Stalinism (Folder 1: 9)
  - War (Folder 1: 10)
- Russian File, circa 1870s-1950s.
  Photographs of Russians and scenes in Russia and the Soviet Union
  - Pre-1917—General (Folder 1: 11)
  - Revolution, 1905 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Revolution, 1917
    - February Revolution (Folder 1: 13)
    - Provisional Government (Folder 1: 14)
    - July Days (Folder 1: 15)
    - Soviets (Folder 1: 16)
    - Soldiers and sailors (Folder 1: 17)
    - Military Revolutionary Committee (Folder 1: 18)
    - Red Guard (Folder 1: 19)
    - Bolshevik leadership (Folder 1: 20)
    - Demonstrations
      - March-September (Folder 1: 21)
      - October-December (Folder 1: 22)
    - October Revolution (Folder 1: 23-24)
  - Civil War, 1918-1921
    - General (Folder 1: 25)
    - Allied intervention (Folder 1: 26)
    - White terror (Folder 1: 27)
    - Red Army (Folder 1: 28)
    - Kronstadt revolt, 1921 (Folder 1: 29)
  - Early Soviet period, 1918-1923
    - General (Folder 1: 30-31)
    - Constituent Assembly, 1918 (Folder 1: 32)
    - Brest-Litovsk Treaty, 1918 (Folder 1: 33)
    - Communist Party (Folder 1: 34)
    - Conferences and meetings (Folder 1: 35)
    - Culture and education (Folder 1: 36)
    - Demonstrations
      - General (Folder 1: 37)
      - Communist International congresses (Folder 1: 38)
    - Eastern peoples (Folder 1: 39)
    - Soviet government (Folder 1: 40)
    - Soviets (Folder 1: 41)
    - Voluntary labor (Folder 1: 42)
  - Late 1920s (Folder 2: 1)
  - 1930s (Folder 2: 2)
  - Communist International
    - First Congress, 1919 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Second Congress, 1920 (Folder 2: 4)
    - Third Congress, 1921 (Folder 2: 5)
    - Fourth Congress, 1922 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Congress of Peoples of the East, 1920 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Red International of Labor Unions (Folder 2: 8)
  - Antonov-Ovseenko, Vladimir (Folder 2: 9)
  - Artistic and literary figures (Folder 2: 10)
  - Bakunin, Mikhail (Folder 2: 11)
  - Bukharin, Nikolai (Folder 2: 12)
  - Chicherin, Georgii (Folder 2: 13)
  - Communist International delegates (Folder 2: 14)
  - Counterrevolutionary Civil War leaders (Folder 2: 15)
  - Dzerzhinskii, Felix (Folder 2: 16)
  - Gorky, Maxim (Folder 2: 17)
  - Ioffe, Adolf (Folder 2: 18)
  - Kamenev, Lev (Folder 2: 19)
  - Kerensky, Alexander (Folder 2: 20)
  - Kollontai, Alexandra (Folder 2: 21)
  - Krupskaia, Nadezhda (Folder 2: 22)
  - Left Oppositionists (Folder 2: 23)
  - Lenin, V. I.
    - 1895-1918 (Folder 2: 24)
    - 1920 (Folder 2: 25)
    - 1921 (Folder 2: 26)
    - Undated (Folder 2: 27)
    - With Leon Trotsky (Folder 2: 28)
    - With others (Folder 2: 29)
    - Drawings and artwork (Folder 2: 30)
    - Lenin cult (Folder 2: 31)
  - Lunacharskii, Anatolii (Folder 2: 32)
  - Mensheviks (Folder 2: 33)
  - Nicholas II, Tsar, and family (Folder 2: 34)
  - Plekhanov, Georgii (Folder 2: 35)
  - Radek, Karl (Folder 2: 36)
  - Rakovskii, Khristian (Folder 2: 37)
  - Revolutionaries, Pre-1917 (Folder 2: 38)
  - Rykov, Aleksei (Folder 2: 39)
  - Serge, Victor (Folder 2: 40)
  - Stalin, Joseph (Folder 2: 41)
  - Sverdlov, Iakov (Folder 2: 42)
  - Zinov'ev, Grigorii (Folder 2: 43)
  - Miscellaneous individuals (Folder 2: 44)
- Leon Trotsky File, 1897-1979. (Box 3)
  Photographs of Leon Trotsky, family and entourage
  - 1917 (Folder 3: 1)
  - 1917-1929 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Prinkipo, Turkey, 1929-1933 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Trip to Copenhagen, Denmark, 1932 (Folder 3: 4)
  - France, 1933-1935 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Norway, 1935-1936 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Mexico, 1937-1940
    - Arrival, 1937 January (Folder 3: 7)
    - Dewey Commission hearings, 1937 April (Folder 3: 8)
    - Portraits of Trotsky (Folder 3: 9)
    - Trotsky in Coyoacán study (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - Trotsky with Nataliia Sedova (Folder 4: 2)
    - Trotsky with others (Folder 4: 3)
    - Coyoacán grounds and study (Folder 4: 4)
    - Coyoacán guards and visitors (Folder 4: 5-6)
    - Contact sheets (Joseph Hansen photographs) (Folder 4: 7-8)
    - Assassination attempt, 1940 May (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Harte, Robert Sheldon (Folder 5: 2)
    - Assassination and funeral, 1940 August (Folder 5: 3)
    - Mercader, Ramon (Folder 5 :4)
  - Memorial meeting, New York, 1940 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Centenary meeting, Mexico, 1979 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Miscellaneous prints (Folder 5: 7-8)
  - Miscellaneous contact sheets (Folder 5: 9-10)
  - Negatives (Folder 5: 11-12)
  - Drawings and artwork (Folder 5: 13)
  - Sedova, Nataliia (Folder 5: 14-15)
  - Sedov, Lev (Folder 5: 16)
- Socialist Workers Party File, circa 1920s-1990s. (Box 6)
  Photographs of Socialist Workers Party leaders, members and associates, and of scenes of Party activities
  - Party leaders (group pictures) (Folder 6 :1-2)
  - Party headquarters, New York and San Francisco (Folder 6: 3)
  - Mountain Spring Camp, New Jersey (Party summer leadership training camp)
    - General, ca. 1949-1962 (Folder 6: 4)
    - Construction project, 1952 (Folder 6: 5)
    - Negatives (Folder 6: 6)
  - Pathfinder Press printshop (Folder 6: 7)
  - Pioneer Publishers sales booth (Folder 6: 8)
  - Anti-fascist demonstrations (against Gerald L. K. Smith), 1938 and 1945 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Mission to Moscow (motion picture) pickets, 1943 (Folder 6: 10)
  - Indonesia solidarity pickets, ca. 1946 (Folder 6: 11)
  - Indochina solidarity pickets, French Consulate, New York, 1947 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Alvin, Milton (Folder 6: 13)
  - Barnes, Jack
    - 1960s and 1970s (Folder 6: 14)
    - 1980s and 1990s (Folder 6: 15)
    - Contact sheets (Folder 6: 16)
  - Bartell, Mike (Folder 6: 17)
  - Bleeker, Sylvia (Folder 6: 18)
  - Booth, Eloise (Folder 6: 19)
  - Breitman, George (Folder 6: 20)
  - Cannon, James P. (Box 7)
    - 1920s (Folder 7: 1)
    - 1930s (Folder 7: 2)
    - 1940s (Folder 7: 3)
    - 1950s (Folder 7: 4)
    - 1960s and 1970s (Folder 7: 5)
    - Memorial meetings, 1974 (Folder 7: 6)
    - Family members (Folder 7: 7)
    - Contact sheets (Folder 7: 8)
    - Negatives (Folder 7: 9)
  - Carlson, Grace (Folder 7: 10)
  - Chester, Bob and Ann (Folder 7: 11)
  - Clarke, George (Folder 7: 12)
  - Cochran, Bert (Folder 7: 13)
  - Coover, Oscar (Folder 7: 14)
  - Coover, Oscar, Jr. (Folder 7: 15)
  - Curtiss, Charles and Lillian (Folder 7: 16)
  - Dunayevskaya, Raya (Folder 7: 17)
  - Farrell, James T. (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Ferguson, Duncan, and Demila Sanders (Folder 8: 2)
  - Garza, Catarino and Richard (Folder 8: 3)
  - Glass, C. Frank (Folder 8: 4)
  - Goldman, Albert (Folder 8: 5)
  - Gordon, Sam (Folder 8: 6)
  - Gray, Laura (Folder 8: 7)
  - Halstead, Fred
    - Portraits, 1961 (Folder 8: 8)
    - World tour, 1968 (Folder 8: 9)
    - 1960s (Folder 8: 10)
    - 1970s (Folder 8: 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 8: 12)
  - Hansen, Al (Folder 8: 13)
  - Hansen, Bea (Folder 8: 14)
  - Hansen, Joseph
    - Early 1930s (Folder 8: 15)
    - Mexico, late 1930s (Folder 8: 16)
      (includes Leon Trotsky)
    - 1940s and 1950s (Folder 8: 17)
    - 1960s and 1970s (Folder 8: 18)
    - Intercontinental Press anniversary banquet, 1974 (Folder 8: 19)
    - Memorial meetings, 1979 (Folder 8: 20)
  - Hansen, Reba (Folder 8: 21)
  - Herron, Edwin (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Karsner, Rose (Folder 9: 2)
  - Keely, Ellen (Folder 9: 3)
  - Kerry, Tom and Karolyn (Folder 9: 4)
  - Konikow, Antoinette (Folder 9: 5)
  - Kutcher, James (Folder 9: 6)
  - Lovell, Frank (Folder 9: 7)
  - Mangan, Sherry (Folder 9: 8)
  - Mayhew, Howard (Folder 9: 9)
  - Muste, A. J. (Folder 9: 10)
  - Novack, George (Folder 9: 11)
  - Preis, Art and Ethel (Folder 9: 12)
  - Reed, Evelyn (Folder 9: 13)
  - Roberts, Dan (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Scholl, Marvel (Folder 10: 2)
  - Shachtman, Max (Folder 10: 3)
  - Sharon, Art (Folder 10: 4)
  - Simpson, Louise (Folder 10: 5)
  - Swabeck, Arne (Folder 10: 6)
  - Trainor, Lawrence and Augusta (Folder 10: 7)
  - Waters, Mary-Alice
    - 1960s and 1970s (Folder 10: 8)
    - 1980s and 1990s (Folder 10: 9)
    - Contact sheets (Folder 10: 10)
  - Weiss, Myra Tanner (Folder 10: 11)
  - Wright, John G. (Folder 10: 12)
  - Individual party members and associates (mainly 1980s and 1990s)
    - A (Folder 10: 13)
    - B (Folder 10: 14)
    - C (Folder 10: 15)
    - D (Folder 10: 16)
    - E (Folder 10: 17)
    - F (Folder 10: 18)
    - G (Folder 10: 19)
    - H (Folder 10: 20)
    - I-J (Folder 10: 21)
    - K (Folder 10: 22)
    - L (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - M (Folder 11: 2)
    - N (Folder 11: 3)
    - P-Q (Folder 11: 4)
    - R (Folder 11: 5)
    - S (Folder 11: 6-7)
    - T (Folder 11: 8)
    - V (Folder 11: 9)
    - W (Folder 11: 10)
    - Y-Z (Folder 11: 11)
- Oversize File, 1871-1990. (Box 12)
  Oversize drawings, photographs, and printed pictorial articles
  - Petrograd Soviet, 1917. (Folder 12: 1)
    Photograph
  - Bolshevik leaders. Drawings by Evelyn Reed of Nikolai Bukharin, Karl Radek, Khristian Rakovskii and Ivan Smirnov (Folder 12: 2)
  - Trotsky, Leon
    - Photograph album of Trotsky in Siberia, 1906, and in Turkey and Norway, 1931-1936 (Folder 12: 3)
    - New York American article by Louise Bryant reporting interview with Trotsky in Moscow, 1922 (Folder 12: 4)
    - Life magazine pictorial articles on Trotsky in Mexico, the Dewey Commission, and the assassination of Trotsky, 1937-1940 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Assassination, 1940. (Folder 12: 6)
      Newspaper articles
    - Italian memorial meeting, 1945. (Folder 12: 7)
      Poster
    - Photograph and drawing. (Folder 12: 8)
      Printed reproductions
  - Socialist Workers Party (Box 13)
    - Works Progress Administration strike participation, 1939. (Folder 13: 1)
      Broadside and newspaper articles
    - Antiwar work, 1967. (Folder 13: 2)
      Photographs
    - COINTELPRO court case, 1981. (Folder 13: 3)
      Drawings by Diane Jacobs of court testimony
    - Lawrence Gelfand court case, 1989. (Folder 13: 4)
      Drawings of court testimony
    - Pathfinder mural, 1990. (Folder 13: 5)
    - Dunne, Vincent Raymond. (Folder 13: 6)
      Drawing by Della Rossa, 1964
    - Hansen, Joseph and Reba. (Folder 13: 7)
    - Reed, Evelyn. (Folder 13: 8)
      Photograph, 1978
  - Paris Commune, 1871. (Folder 13: 9)
    Pictorial newspaper articles
  - Spanish Civil War. (Folder 13: 10)
    Photographs, 1936-1937
  - World War II. (Folder 13: 11)
    Printed reproductions of photographs of the Jewish Holocaust and of the Hiroshima atomic bomb
  - French General Strike, 1968. (Folder 13: 12)
    Printed reproductions of photographs
  - Peng, Shu-tse, and Chen Pi-lan. (Folder 13: 13)
  - Pinochet, Augusto. (Folder 13: 14)
    Caricature by Ivan for The Militant
  - X, Malcolm. (Folder 13: 15)
- General Subject File, circa 1900s-1990s. (Box 14)
  Photographs of individuals, including American and other leftist figures, Trotskyist leaders from outside the United States, and figures of general historical interest
  - Communist Party of the United States leaders, 1920s (Folder 14: 1)
  - Diego Rivera murals, New Workers School, New York City (Folder 14: 2)
  - China massacres, 1927-1931 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Chinese Trotskyist leaders (Folder 14: 4)
  - Spanish Civil War
    - Francoists (Folder 14: 5)
    - Republicans (Folder 14: 6)
  - Vietnamese nationalist and Trotskyist leaders (Folder 14: 7)
  - Debs, Eugene V. (Folder 14: 8)
  - De Leon, Daniel (Folder 14: 9)
  - Deutscher, Isaac (Folder 14: 10)
  - Du Bois, W. E. B. (Folder 14: 11)
  - Fonseca, Carlos (Folder 14: 12)
  - Frank, Pierre (Folder 14: 13)
  - Jones, Mary Harris "Mother" (Folder 14: 14)
  - Jungclas, Georg (Folder 14: 15)
  - Kun, Bela (Folder 14: 16)
  - Leon, Abram (Folder 14: 17)
  - Mandel, Ernest and Gisela (Folder 14: 18)
  - Mink, George (Folder 14: 19)
  - Peng, Shu-tse, and Chen Pi-lan (Folder 14: 20)
  - Rodinson, Maxime (Folder 14: 21)
  - Rosmer, Alfred and Marguerite (Folder 14: 22)
  - Tabata, I. B., and Franz J. T. Lee (Folder 14: 23)
  - X, Malcolm (Box 15)
    - Pre-1964 (Folder 15: 1)
    - U.S., 1964 (Folder 15: 2)
    - Africa, 1964 (Folder 15: 3)
    - Militant Labor Forums, New York, 1964-1965 (Folder 15: 4)
    - Schomberg Center, New York, 1964-1965 (Folder 15: 5)
    - 1965 (Folder 15: 6)
    - Unidentified occasions (Folder 15: 7)
    - Assassination and funeral, 1965 (Folder 15: 8)
    - Associates (Folder 15: 9)
    - Drawings and artwork (Folder 15: 10)
  - Notable individuals
    - A (Folder 15: 11)
    - B (Folder 15: 12)
    - C (Folder 15: 13)
    - D (Folder 15: 14)
    - E (Folder 15: 15)
    - F (Folder 15: 16)
    - G (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - H (Folder 16: 2)
    - J (Folder 16: 3)
    - K (Folder 16: 4)
    - L (Folder 16: 5)
    - M (Folder 16: 6)
    - N (Folder 16: 7)
    - O (Folder 16: 8)
    - P (Folder 16: 9)
    - R (Folder 16: 10)
    - S (Folder 16: 11)
    - T (Folder 16: 12)
    - V (Folder 16: 13)
    - W (Folder 16: 14)
    - Y-Z (Folder 16: 15)
- Publications File, 1973-1991. (Box 17)
  Photographs used in Pathfinder Press publications, arranged chronologically by publication
  - Cannon, James P. Letters from Prison. 2nd edition., 1973 (Folder 17: 1)
  - Trotsky, Leon. Writings of Leon Trotsky, 1929., 1975 (Folder 17: 2)
  - Trotsky, Leon. The History of the Russian Revolution., 1980 (Folder 17: 3)
  - Castro, Fidel. Women and the Cuban Revolution: Speeches and Documents. By Fidel Castro, Vilma Espin and others; edited by Elizabeth Stone., 1981 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Weissberg, Arnold. Nicaragua: An Introduction to the Sandinista Revolution., 1981 (Folder 17: 5)
  - Wang, Diane. Report from Vietnam and Kampuchea. By Diane Wang and Steve Clark., 1984 (Folder 17: 6)
  - Castro, Fidel. U.S. Hands Off the Mideast! Cuba Speaks Out at the United Nations. By Fidel Castro and Ricardo Alarcon., 1990 (Folder 17: 7)
  - Mandela, Nelson. Intensifiquemos la lucha: Discursos en Africa, Europa y Norteamerica., 1990 (Folder 17: 8)
  - Communist International. Congress (2nd: 1920: Petrograd, Russia) Workers of the World and Oppressed Peoples, Unite! Proceedings and Documents of the Second Congress, 1920. Edited by John Riddell., 1991
    - Volume 1 (Folder 17: 9)
    - Volume 2 (Folder 17: 10)
  - Nouvelle Internationale. No. 4., 1991 (Folder 17: 11)
- Numerical Contact Sheets File, circa 1960s-1990s.
  Contact sheets numerically arranged by negative number. Not all numbers are represented
  - 1-499 (Folder 17: 12)
  - 500-999 (Folder 17: 13)
  - 1000-1499 (Folder 17: 14)
  - 1500-1999 (Folder 17: 15)
  - 2000-2499 (Folder 17: 16)
  - 2500-2999 (Folder 17: 17)
  - 3000-3199 (Folder 17: 18)
  - 3200-3399 (Folder 17: 19)
  - 3600-3799 (Folder 17: 20)
  - 3800-3999 (Folder 17: 21)
  - 4000-4199 (Folder 17: 22)
  - 4400-4599 (Folder 17: 23)
  - 4600-4799 (Folder 17: 24)
  - 4800-4999 (Folder 17: 25)
  - 7000-7999 (Folder 17: 26)
  - 8000-8999 (Folder 17: 27)
  - 9000-9499 (Folder 17: 28)
  - 9500-9999 (Folder 17: 29)
  - 10,200-10,399 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - 10,400-10,599 (Folder 18: 2)
  - 11,400-11,599 (Folder 18: 3)
  - 11,600-11,799 (Folder 18: 4)
  - 11,800-11,999 (Folder 18: 5)
  - 12,000-12,199 (Folder 18: 6)
  - 13,000-13,199 (Folder 18: 7)
  - 13,200-13,399 (Folder 18: 8)
  - 13,400-13,599 (Folder 18: 9)
  - 13,600-13,699 (Folder 18: 10)
  - 13,700-13,799 (Folder 18: 11)
  - 14,000-14,999 (Folder 18: 12)
  - 15,000-15,999 (Folder 18: 13)
  - 16,000-16,999 (Folder 18: 14)
  - 17,000-17,999 (Folder 18: 15)
  - 18,000-18,999 (Folder 18: 16)
  - 19,000-19,999 (Folder 18: 17)
- Numerical Negative File, circa 1960s-1990s. (Box 19)
  Negatives numerically arranged. Not all numbers are represented
  - 1-1805
  - 1819-4623 (Box 20)
  - 4624-10,423 (Box 21)
  - 10,424-13,607 (Box 22)
  - 13,609-14,750 (Box 23)
  - 14,751-15,450 (Box 24)
  - 15,453-16,150 (Box 25)
  - 16,151-16,700 (Box 26)
  - 16,701-17,209 (Box 27)
  - 17,210-17,658 (Box 28)
  - 17,659-17,959 (Box 29)
  - 17,960-18,381 (Box 30)
  - 18,382-18,789 (Box 31)
  - 18,790-19,214 (Box 32)
  - 19,215-19,538 (Box 33)
  - H1-H635
- Filmstrips (Box 34)
- Card File. (Box 35)
  Names of individuals depicted, alphabetically arranged, correlated with negative numbers
  - A-L
  - M-Z (Box 36)